juliareda.eu 2018-12-28

# Julia Reda – Privacy Policy

## Who we are

The office of MEP Julia Reda  
Parlement européen  
ASP 05F158  
60, rue Wiertz  
1047 Brussels, BELGIUM  
+32(0)2 28 45732  
julia.reda@europarl.europa.eu

Data collected by this website is stored on a server located in Germany and provided by [fnordcordia GbR](https://fnordserver.eu/en/). You may find [their privacy policy here](https://fnordserver.eu/en/privacy-policy/).

## personal data we collect

### I.

Upon your request and **expression of consent** , we collect the following data for the purpose of providing services to you. Your data is not used for any other purposes or shared with third parties. It is removed upon your withdrawal of consent/request to terminate these services.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will be saved on your computer for one year or until you delete them.

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognise and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

### Newsletter

If you decide to subscribe to our newsletter, we collect your email address. Every mailing includes clear instructions to opt out of receiving future messages.

### II.

Based on our **legitimate interests** , we collect the following data for the purpose of running this website. Your data is not used for any other purposes or shared with third parties. It is removed upon your request.

### statistics

We use Matomo, an open source web analytics platform running on our server, to improve the user experience on our website and help you find the information you are looking for. Matomo allows us to analyse the behaviour of website visitors to identify potential pitfalls such as missing pages, search engine indexing issues, the popularity of certain posts, etc.

Matomo is used to process the following personal data: Unique User ID set by Matomo; cookies set by Matomo containing the User ID and which website you visited prior to this one; and also: Date and time, Title of the page being viewed, URL of the page being viewed, URL of the page that was viewed prior to the current page, Screen resolution, Time in local timezone, Files that were clicked and downloaded, Link clicks to an outside domain, Pages generation time, Country, region, city, Main Language of the browser, User Agent of the browser.

We are minimising the impact of this tracking on your privacy by automatically anonymising your IP address, which could be used to personally identify you even beyond this website, and thus choosing the least intrusive way of gathering the data necessary for us to improve our website.

**You may opt out** of this tracking at any time by activating the “Do Not Track” setting in your browser or by using the following form:

### III. Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, charts, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor had visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

## Your rights pertaining your data

If you have left comments on this site or subscribed to a newsletter, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we rectify or erase any personal data we hold about you.

  * The right to withdraw consent
  * The right of access
  * The right to erasure
  * The right to rectification
  * The right to data portability
  * The right to object
  * Notification of data breaches
  * The right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority

To the extent possible under law, the creator has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this work.
